NATASHA PIERRE-LOUIS

Email: natashapl@natashasworld.com
Website: http://natashasworld.com
Location: Fort Lauderdale, FL

OBJECTIVE

I have over 10 years of experience with design and front-end development. I have strong HTML and CSS skills, and am very comfortable with JavaScript, Java, PHP and .NET. Some additional skills include responsive web design, wireframing and producing mockups. I've worked within an agile environment for over 5 years and became a Certified ScrumMaster in 2012. I also have a Bachelors degree in Graphic Design and have learned a lot about user experience from some amazing UX Architects. I'm interested in pursuing a UI Designer/Front-End Developer position.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Front-End Development
- UI/Graphic Design
- Design Thinking

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Agile Development (Scrum)
- Wireframe Creation

EXPERIENCE

Citrix Systems, Senior Web Developer

09/2010 - 02/2015

- Developed cross-browser compatible, standards-compliant and responsive web pages using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and template scripting, according to software requirements and design specifications
- Created the User Interface and Visual Designs for applications while focusing on user needs and optimal user experience
- Worked closely with UX Designers and regularly attended UX Meetups in order to expand my knowledge of human-centered design
- Debugged, maintained and updated applications within the Google Web Toolkit framework as well as Java-based templates such as Freemarker
- Worked as the dedicated Front-end Developer for <u>Citrix Project Accelerator</u>, <u>Citrix Project Serenity Beta and Paper Cloud WordPress site</u>
- Volunteered to help migrate <u>A Kids' Brain Tumor Cure PLGA Foundation's</u> site to WordPress
- Kept current with technical trends and incorporated them within assignments as appropriate
- Recommended improvements and changes in designs and gave professional appraisal on implementation of the design as planned and/or executed
- Analyzed requirements, and contributed to software requirements and design specifications for projects of significant scope

BGT Partners, UI Developer

01/2010 - 09/2010

- Developed cross-browser compatible and standards-compliant HTML/XHTML Pages based on Visual Designs provided by the Graphic Design team
- Created reusable templates within PHP framework

- Debugged and fixed layout issues within development team's .NET and JavaScript framework
- Documented and maintained coding, commenting and validation

Automated Healthcare Solutions, Multimedia Specialist

01/2009 - 10/2009

- Captured and edited videos with Final Cut Pro
- Created Interactive DVDs with DVD Studio Pro
- Created patent drawings
- Created the User Interface and Visual Designs for web based applications
- Developed and designed cross-browser pages within a .NET environment
- Documented and maintained coding, commenting, validation and testing standards

Kaplan University, HTML Developer/Designer

12/2007 - 01/2009

- Created Visual Designs for web pages based on UI Team prototypes
- Developed and designed cross-browser pages for a .NET environment
- Debugged and fixed layout issues within development team's ASP and JavaScript framework
- Documented and maintained coding, commenting, validation and testing standards
- Developed HTML Style Guides based on finalized templates

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Graphic Design, December 2003

Florida Atlantic University, Davie, FL, GPA – 3.4 Design Against Fur Student Poster Competition, Honorable Mention, 2003

Associate of Science, Computer Graphics and Designs, April 1996

Keiser College, Fort Lauderdale, FL, GPA - 3.8

SOFTWARE AND TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite, Axure, Eclipse, IntelliJ, GIT, DVD Studio Pro, Final Cut Pro, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Visual Studios, phpMyAdmin, Quark, Visio

OPERATING SYSTEMS

Mac OS, Windows

REFERENCES

Available upon request